<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>human computer interaction on Mike Quigley</title>
    <link>https://quig.info/blog/tags/human-computer-interaction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in human computer interaction on Mike Quigley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:15:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quig.info/blog/tags/human-computer-interaction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mirror Music</title>
      <link>https://quig.info/blog/posts/mirror-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 20:15:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quig.info/blog/posts/mirror-music/</guid>
      <description>Mirror music is an interactive synthesizer that generates random pitches within a user specified key, triggered by motion, and characterized in range and timbre by color.
Video input is split into a grid of 16 squares, or &amp;ldquo;pixels&amp;rdquo;. Each pixel is analyzed for motion and color data. When motion in a pixel is detected, the color data at that moment is sent to 1 of 16 poly~ instances that generates a random pitch within the specified key, played for the specified length with attack, decay, sustain, and release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Feedback in a Laptop Instrument</title>
      <link>https://quig.info/blog/posts/visual-feedback-in-a-laptop-instrument/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 19:53:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quig.info/blog/posts/visual-feedback-in-a-laptop-instrument/</guid>
      <description>Over time instrumentalists come to understand the distinctions between primary physical actions that produce sound and ancillary actions that aid in expressing musical or emotional information, which can be vital to audience understanding. It is possible that the loss of haptic feedback makes the properties of a musical instrument less understandable to both performer and audience. Perhaps then visual feedback can allow an instrumentalist to better understand the limitations of his or her instrument when no such haptic feedback exists, as is the case with many musical systems that incorporate live video interaction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
